http://fpdcc.com/privacy-policy-terms-of-use/

Skip to main content
Search website:
On this page:Privacy PolicyTerms of UsePrivacy PolicyPurposeThis Policy is a disclosure statement to users of Forest Preserves of Cook County (“Forest Preserves”) websites: fpdcc.com and map.fpdcc.com.  The policy addresses the collection, use, disclosure, and security of information that may be obtained by the Forest Preserves and third parties through the use of Forest Preserves websites.  A copy of this policy shall be accessible via a persistent hyperlink labeled “Privacy Policy & Terms of Use” on the bottom of every fpdcc.com web page and within the navigation menu of map.fpdcc.com.Areas AffectedThis policy applies to the use of fpdcc.com and map.fpdcc.com websites operated by the Forest Preserves.Changes to This PolicyThe Forest Preserves may, from time to time, modify this Privacy Policy to reflect legal, technological and other developments. In that event, the changes will appear on this page along with the date of the latest update.Policy1. Information Collected by the Forest PreservesIn order to improve the content and usability of Forest
Preserves websites, the Forest Preserves automatically collects basic website
browsing information from Forest Preserves website users.The
Forest Preserves uses this information to identify site performance needs, to
ensure compatibility with the technology used by the Forest Preserves website
visitors, and to generally add and improve services offered on the Forest Preserves
websites.  The
Forest Preserves does not collect data for commercial purposes and does not
sell, exchange or otherwise distribute the data collected by the Forest
Preserves websites for commercial purposes.2. Information Submitted to the Forest Preserves WebsitesDuring a session on the Forest Preserves websites, a user may
affirmatively submit information to the Forest Preserves by, among other means,
electronic mail (“email”) or by filling in and submitting an online
form or by allowing map.fpdcc.com to track your location. Such affirmatively
submitted information is stored in a secure environment and will be used by the
Forest Preserves in furtherance of its governmental purposes.The
Forest Preserves does not rent or sell personally identifiable information
(i.e., information such as name, address, phone number, email, etc., that
identifies a user as a particular person), nor would the Forest Preserves
exchange or trade such information with third parties without a user’s explicit
permission. 3. CookiesCookies are text files, or entries in larger files, utilized to
distinguish between visitors to a website, and to track information during
multiple visits to a website.  Cookie storage can be either temporary
(“Session”) or permanent (“Persistent”).  A Session cookie is deleted when
you exit your web browser and a Persistent cookie remains on your hard drive
until you manually delete it or the cookie expires.  The Forest Preserves
may use both types of cookies to improve the content and usability of Forest Preserves
websites.The
use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet websites. Most Internet
web browsers may be customized to reject cookies, to only accept or reject
cookies by user intervention, or to delete cookies. Rejecting and/or removing cookies,
however, may lead to loss of functionality on those Forest Preserves website
pages requiring cookies to function fully.4. Third Party ServicesIn order to improve the content and usability of Forest
Preserves websites, the Forest Preserves enlists the services of third
parties.  In such cases, the third party’s use of Forest Preserves website
user data is restricted by and subject to the third party’s own Terms of
Service and Privacy Policy. 5. ChildrenNone of the Forest Preserves websites specifically solicit information from minors or seeks to determine whether the visitor is a minor. Consequently, because such information will not be specifically identified as being from minors, users of the Forest Preserves websites should be aware that personally identifiable information submitted to the Forest Preserves websites by minors will be subject to being treated in the same manner as information given by an adult and may become subject to public access.Terms & Conditions of UseAccess to the Forest Preserves websites is provided subject to the following terms and conditions. Please read these terms carefully as use of these sites constitutes acceptance of all of the following terms and conditions:1. Disclaimer of LiabilityNEITHER
THE FOREST PRESERVES, ITS PRESIDENT, BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS NOR ANY OF ITS
EMPLOYEES OR AGENTS SHALL BE HELD LIABLE FOR ANY IMPROPER OR INCORRECT USE OF
THE INFORMATION DESCRIBED AND/OR CONTAINED HEREIN AND ASSUMES NO RESPONSIBILITY
FOR ANYONE’S USE OF SUCH INFORMATION. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE FOREST PRESERVES ITS
PRESIDENT, BOARD OFCOMMISSIONERS, ITS EMPLOYEES, OR AGENTS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES
(INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OR SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;
LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON
ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT
(INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
SYSTEM, WEBSITE, OR LINKED WEBSITES, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH
DAMAGES. THIS DISCLAIMER OF LIABILITY APPLIES TO ANY DAMAGES OR INJURY,
INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THOSE CAUSED BY ANY FAILURE OF PERFORMANCE, ERROR,
OMISSION, INTERRUPTION, DELETION, DEFECT, DELAY IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION,
COMPUTER VIRUS, COMMUNICATION LINE FAILURE, THEFT OR DESTRUCTION OR
UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO, ALTERATION OF, OR USE OF RECORD, WHETHER FOR BREACH OF
CONTRACT, TORTIOUS BEHAVIOR, NEGLIGENCE, OR UNDER ANY OTHER CAUSE OF ACTION.2. Disclaimer of Warranties and Accuracy of DataNO
WARRANTY, EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, IS MADE REGARDING ACCURACY, ADEQUACY,
COMPLETENESS, LEGALITY, RELIABILITY OR USEFULNESS OF ANY INFORMATION POSTED ON
THE FOREST PRESERVES WEBSITES. THIS DISCLAIMER APPLIES TO BOTH ISOLATED AND
AGGREGATE USES OF THE INFORMATION. THE FOREST PRESERVES PROVIDES THIS
INFORMATION ON AN “AS IS” BASIS. ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, FREEDOM FROM CONTAMINATION BY
COMPUTER VIRUSES AND NON-INFRINGEMENT OF PROPRIETARY RIGHTS ARE DISCLAIMED.
CHANGES MAY BE PERIODICALLY MADE TO THE INFORMATION HEREIN; THESE CHANGES MAY
OR MAY NOT BE INCORPORATED IN ANY NEW VERSION OF THE PUBLICATION. IF YOU HAVE
OBTAINED INFORMATION FROM ANY OF THE FOREST PRESERVES WEB PAGES FROM A SOURCE
OTHER THAN THE FOREST PRESERVES WEBSITE, BE AWARE THAT ELECTRONIC DATA CAN BE
ALTERED SUBSEQUENT TO ORIGINAL DISTRIBUTION. DATA CAN ALSO QUICKLY BECOME OUT
OF DATE. IT IS RECOMMENDED THAT CAREFUL ATTENTION BE PAID TO THE CONTENTS OF
ANY DATA ASSOCIATED WITH A FILE, AND THAT THE ORIGINATOR OF THE DATA OR
INFORMATION BE CONTACTED WITH ANY QUESTIONS REGARDING APPROPRIATE USE.3. Disclaimer of EndorsementThe
Forest Preserves is a distributor of content sometimes supplied by third
parties and users. Any opinions, advice, statements, services, offers, or other
information or content expressed or made available by third parties, including
information providers, users, or others, are those of the respective author(s)
or distributor(s) and do not necessarily state or reflect those of the Forest
Preserves and shall not be used for advertising or product endorsement
purposes. Reference herein to any specific commercial products, process, or
service by trade name, trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise, does not
constitute or imply its endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the Forest
Preserves, its President, Board of Commissioners, its employees, or agents.4. Disclaimer for External LinksThe
Forest Preserves may provide links to content supplied by third parties and
users. The existence and/or provision of those links neither constitutes nor
implies endorsement of the destination or departure website(s) or of the
content, viewpoint, accuracy, opinions, policy(ies), product(s), accessibility
or privacy policy of said destination or departure website(s). Nor does any
link between the Forest Preserves websites and a third-party website imply
sponsorship of such website, or the creator of such website. When you link to a
third-party website, you are subject to the privacy policy and terms of service
of the third party’s website.5. Disclaimer of Duty to Continue Provision of DataDue
to the dynamic nature of the Internet, resources that are free and publicly
available one day may require a fee or restricted access the next, and the
location of items may change as menus, homepages, and files are reorganized.
You expressly agree that use of the Forest Preserves websites is at your sole
risk. The Forest Preserves does not warrant that the service will be
uninterrupted or error free. The documents and related graphics published on
this server could contain technical inaccuracies or typographical errors.
Changes are periodically added to the information herein. The Forest Preserves may
make improvements and/or changes in the information and/or programs described
herein at any time.6. ContentTo
promote open and productive dialogue, and in the spirit of fair and transparent
access to the Forest Preserves websites, users are hereby advised that all
postings, including any links to 3rd-party sites, shall be subject to limited
monitoring for appropriateness. For purposes herein, appropriateness is defined
as postings that are relevant to Forest Preserves official governmental
business, responsive to the issue(s) being discussed, and phrased in respectful
and appropriate language for the general public.  Content that is
commercial, self-promotional, campaign-related, prurient, abusive, or that
contains discriminatory speech, including but not limited to, hate speech based
on race, gender, sex, national origin, age, sexual orientation, religion, or disability
is considered inappropriate for posting on the Forest Preserves websites.
If content is determined to be inappropriate, such content either will not be
posted or will be removed from the website.7. Choice of LawConstruction
of the disclaimers above and resolution of disputes thereof are governed by the
laws of the State of Illinois. The laws of the State of Illinois, U.S.A., shall
apply to all uses of this data and this system. By use of this system and any
data contained therein, you agree that your use shall conform to all applicable
laws and regulations and you shall not violate the rights of any third parties.8. SecurityThe
Forest Preserves has taken several security measures to safeguard the integrity
of the Forest Preserves websites, including but not limited to authentication,
monitoring, and encryption.This
information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or
other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided
via the Forest Preserves websites.9. Web Accessibility ComplianceThe
Forest Preserves is committed to providing equal, multi-platform access to fpdcc.com.
The Forest Preserves has adopted W3C Standards for Accessibility for fpdcc.com.
Learn more on our Accessibility Page.10. Intellectual PropertyThe content of Forest Preserves websites is copyrighted and may contain some third-party content that is used with permission of the third party. Users are notified, therefore, that one should presume the need to obtain permission from the copyright holder before reproducing or otherwise using images/graphics from this website. Contact fpdcc.info@cookcountyil.gov for questions about reproducing or using content from Forest Preserves websites.The LatestCOVID-19: Events, Locations & Precautions2021 Picnic & Event Permits Now AvailablePosition Papers: Land Acquisition & Racial EquityPartnering with the American Indian CenterUnexpected, Rare Plants Returning to Recently Restored Forest Preserves View All News »
